PUSHPITA MOHAPATRA () Featured

Cloud Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Release
Engineering, Application Deployment, IT Infrastructure Support, Cloud
Infrastructure, Technical Support, Configuration Management, Installation, BMC
Remedy, Bootstrap, Jenkins, Docker, Oracle, DNS, AWS



Current Designation: Engineer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Current Company: CSS Corp Highest Degree:

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: cloud engineer,software developer,software engineering,it infrastructure support,cloud

infrastructure, configuration

management,installation,bootstrap,docker,dns,dhcp,apache,virtualization,vmware,vmotion,networking

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

2+ years of IT Industry experience with Cloud Admin.

Involved in the functional usage and deployment of applications in Apache Tomcat Server.

Experience in using Tomcat and Apache web servers for deployments and for hosting tools.

Created and managed several cron jobs like backing up log files and configuration files.

Using the nexus repository to store the artifact versions.

Managed Amazon Web Services like EC2, S3 Bucket, RDS, EBS, ELB, Auto-Scaling, AMI and IAM through AWS Console. To acquire the position of a DevOps Configuration & Build and Release Engineer in a well-established organization where I can utilize my knowledge in information technology field for the betterment of the organization.

Work Experience

CSS Corp as Cloud Engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

To acquire the position of a DevOps Configuration & Build and Release Engineer in a well-established organization where I can utilize my knowledge in information technology field for the betterment of the organization

CSS Corp as Engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

I was working as a cloud engineer in css Corp and experienced on building the infrastructure in Aws cloud.

CSS Corp as Engineeer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

I was working as a cloud engineer and had experience on deploying of web application

CSS Corp as Engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020 CSS Corp as Engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

i was working as a cloud engineer

CSS Corp as engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

worked as a cloud engineer

CSS Corp as Engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

I was working as a cloud engineer in css Corp. I do have hands-on experience on Aws cloud infrastructure.

CSS Corp as engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

I worked as a cloud engineer in css Corp.

CSS Corp as Cloud Engineer Jul 2018 to Jul 2018

RESPONSIBILITIES DETAILS: * Installing, configuring and maintaining of RHEL on Dell servers by CDROM and Network * installation types * Installation, configuration and maintenance of Logical Volume Manager (LVM) * Configuration of SSH and providing user level and system level security * Solving day to day problems and following it up through ticketing system * Memory and swap space management * Installation of software Packages, managing and checking the integrity of the installed packages * using rpm and yum local repository. * Tracking system capacity and correcting any issues, answering technical queries and reported * problems * Configuring and maintaining NFS server/client. * Troubleshooting file system corruption, system boot failures and reported problems. * Security implementation through ACL and special permissions * Creating partitions, managing file systems, labelling * Providing network level security using TCP wrappers and CSF . * Prepared release notes, test report and other artifacts for delivery . * Monitored product lines for a failure and reported issues to teams after first level analysis * Configuring the "crone tab" for nightly build and deployment. * Providing solutions to developers for check-ins, checkouts, build failure related issues. * Involved to Deploy the War files in Apache Tomcat server * Having knowledge on Docker image creation and deployment. * Work with Development Team and testing team to establish a build schedule. * Configured and Monitoring the Application/Servers using Nagios

- * Tracking system capacity and correcting any issues, answering technical queries and reported problems
- * Setting up EC2 instances and deployment of client applications like Apache, Apache on AWS EC2 instances.
- * Configuring S3 bucket permissions, versioning, and logging.
- * Creating and managing Elastic Load balancer and also managing EBS and EBS Snapshots Configuring Auto scaling Policies of EC2 instances based on CPU, network and Memory.

CSS Corp as Engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

I worked as a cloud engineer in CSS corp

CSS Corp as Engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

I was working as a cloud engineer in css Corp and I also have hands-on experience on Aws cloud and networking.

CSS Corp as Engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

I was working as a cloud engineer in css Corp with 2.4 years of experience.

CSS Corp as engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

i was working as a cloud engineer in CSS corp with 2.4 yrs of experience

CSS Corp as Engineer Jul 2018 to Till Date

I was working as a cloud engineer .and willing pursue a professionally satisfying growth and challenging career. Seeking a quality environment where my knowledge can be shared and enriched for the growth of the organization and self.

Business Standard as Cloud Engineer Jul 2018 to Jul 2018

CSS Corp as engineer Jul 2018 to Oct 2020

i was working as a cloud engineer

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from BPUT UNIVERSITY in 2016

PG: in 0

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Apache, Niginx, Tomcat.			
Amazon Web Services, Shell			
Nagios, manitou, Cloud watch			
NFS,NTP,DNS,DHCP,NFS, Ngnix, ELB			
BMC Remedy, Snow service			
MS SQL , Oracle , MS Access, Dynamo DB			
Linux, RHEL, Ubuntu, Mac OS X			
Windows server 2008/12/16			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time